

THOMAS LEMAR AWS/DEVOPS ENGINEER

Phone: 808-242-7291

E-mail: thomasl@gmail.com

GitHub: github.com/ThomasL

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/TL

SUMMARY

As a DevOps Cloud Engineer, my strong everyday-learning mentality combined with open-mindness and determination enables me to learn new skill sets and adapt them onto new environments faster. Thanks to my experiences working multicultural environments, I could easily be part of multicultural/multifunctional IT teams with complete coherence. Having conducted Agile methodologies integrated with CI/CD Practices,

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Healthmade Solutions (2015 - present)

- Direct software design
- Evaluate interface between hardware and software
- Advice customers regarding maintenance of software system

JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

RealPro Software (2014 - 2015)

- Stored, retrieved, and manipulated data
- Modified existing softwares to correct errors
- Prepared detailed reports

SKİLLS

- Python, SQL, HTML, CSS
- Linux, Git, GitHub
- Cloud(AWS), CloudFormation
- Jenkins, Dockers, Kubernetes
- Jira, ClickUp, Slack
- Ansible, Terraform
- Scrum/Kanban

- Motivation
- Initiative
- Leadership
- Teamwork
- Problem Solving
- Critical Thinking
- Flexibility

PROJECTS

- Microservice Architecture for Phonebook Web Application (Python Flask) with MySQL using Kubernetes
- Jenkins Pipeline for Dockerized Phonebook Application (Python Flask & MySQL) Deployed on Docker Swarm
- Dockerization of Bookstore Web API (Python Flask) with MySQL
- Phonebook Application (Python Flask) deployed on AWS Application Load Balancer with Auto Scaling and Relational Database Service using AWS Cloudformation
- Kittens Carousel Static Website deployed on AWS Cloudfront, S3 and Route 53 using Cloudformation

AWS Hands-On Experience on;

• EC2, CloudFormation, ECR, DynamoDB, CloudFront, S3, API GW, Lambda, EFS, Boto3, CloudWatch, RDS, MariaDB, ALB with ASG, Apache, Nginx, Snapshots, Volumes, VPC, WordPress, Route53, Certificate Manager, IAM, AMI.

DevOps Hands-On Experience on;

- Docker: Installing basic operations, handling volumes, networking, image basic operations, compose operations, dockerize to-do app on python-flask, swarm basic operations, swarm network managing services, secrets, tasks.
- Kubernetes: Installing and basic operations, networking service discovery, Microservice deployment and auto-scaling, managing secrets and configmaps, pods and volumes, managing Kubernetes cluster with EKS, dynamic volume provisioning and ingress.
- Ansible: Using modules with ad-hoc commands, using playbooks with tasks, using secrets, provisioning a web and db server with dynamic websites, working with dynamic inventory, using roles.
- Jenkins: Installing, building Jenkins job, building Jenkins pipeline, installing and configuring tomcat, deployment to staging environment, building pipeline with docker ECR.
- Terraform: Installing Terraform and building AWS infrastructure with Terraform.
- Nexus: Installing and using Proxy Repository on EC2 Instance.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Clarusway AWS/DevOps Course Certification
- Certified Cloud Practitioner
- Solutions Architect Associate Certification

EDUCATION

SCHOOL

CLARUSWAY IT TRAINING • School of The Arts (2020 - 2021)

COMPUTER ENGINEERING • New City College (2010 - 2014)

LANGUAGE

ENGLISH

Native Language

GERMAN

• Elementary(Speaking, Writing) Intermediate(Reading)